BAZILUC MARIAN

Web Developer with over 1 year experience in Front-End Development, implementing web applications specialized in SPA development using React ecosystem. I've recently finished a front-end course which lasted 5 months at Wantsome, "the friendly IT Academy". This course helped me to understand important base concepts of Js language/Node, React, HTML & CSS, which can be used to build a modern web application.

I am looking for a position as Front-End Developer where I can enhance my skills, challenge my abilities, learn new things and work inside a team of professionals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

DigitalPoint Iasi, Romania

Front-End Developer

Jul 2020 to Oct 2020

- Collaborated with web designers and back-end developers to build the company's official website.
- Responsible for developing layouts and reusable components, creating responsive design for different devices using libraries like Bootstrap or Material UI.
- I optimized the Critical Rendering Path by splitting the bundle into smaller chunks, code splitting (e.g. loading components and attachments lazily).
- Migrating application to latest version of React using React Hooks.

Perla Venusului Constanta, Romania

Bartender

June 2015 to September 2019

- Working as a bartender where I learned how to satisfy the customer's needs.
- Maintained stock levels in order to prevent shortages of items.
- Accurately balanced cash register at all times.

SKILLS

Technical: HTML CSS JavaScript ReactJS React-Native(basic) Redux Express.js

Bootstrap Material-UI SCSS styled-components git

Management: Kanban Methodology Scrum

EDUCATION

Wantsome, the friendly IT Academy

11.2019-04.2020

Front-End Course, Iasi, Romania

Faculty of Electronics, Telecommunications and Information Technology

Iasi, Romania 08.2010 - Present

Grigore Moisil Computer Science High School

09.2013 - 06.2017

Iasi, Romania

Email	Mobile	LinkedIn
bazilucmarian98@yahoo.com	(0757) 357 597	www.linkedin.com/in/baziluc-
		marian/

PORTOFOLIO

http://baz-portofolio.herokuapp.com/portofolio

1.BAZ DEVELOPMENT

Web application built with Create-React-App, Firebase, React Router and Material-UI. The purpose of this application is to gain more knowledge about Material-UI. It is a presentation website where the user has access to information about some software services offered by company like iOS/Android App Development, Custom Software Development or Website Development. User can request an estimate price for a service, but he has to complete a quiz. After that the price of that service will be displayed. I applied diffferent image optimization strategies, I used Material-UI grid system to align complex layouts perfectly, displaying some animation using react-lottic package, creating a theme to manipulate styling system for entire application, sending emails through Node.js, making network requests and displaying feedback like loading spinners.In the end, I migrated application from Create-React-App to Next.js for server-side rendering which is important for Search Engine Optimization (SEO).

GitHub Web

https://github.com/bazilucmarian/baz-development-CRA-

https://github.com/bazilucmarian/bazdevelopment-Next.js-

https://bazdev.netlify.app/

2.BAZ CLOTHING

E-commerce application built with Create-React-App, Firebase, React Router, Redux, SCSS, StripeAPI. The application is an online store where users can add to cart some products. Users can manipulate products through dropdown cart which will redirect them to checkout page where can increase/decrease amount of products or remove a specific product from shopping cart. After that the total value is displayed and user can simulate card payment filling the form provided by Stripe.

GitHub Web

https://github.com/bazilucmarian/SHOP

https://baz-clothing.herokuapp.com/

3.FISH STORE

"Fish Store" application built with Create-React-App, Express.js, Context API, Material UI, the application is divided into three parts: products list, shopping cart and inventory. In inventory are products and each product contain a form with ther initial state. User can manipulate the state and products will change automatically, achieving communication between components. Also, new products can be added to the inventory, or existing one can be deleted. I maintained application state using Context API and I used localStorage for persisting data in browser. After that, user can generate a pdf document with all products added to the cart. In order to create this I used "html-pdf" package in server created with Express.js. I created a post request with all data from shopping cart and if the status code is 200 PDF document will be formed, and after that the user can download the document based on a get request.

GitHub Web

https://github.com/bazilucmarian/React--

FishStore

https://store-fish.herokuapp.com/